William Jensen

Address: Somerville 02143, United States

Phone number: 774-571-7904

Email address: wjensen.games@gmail.com

Web: www.wjjensen.com



Objective

I am a self-taught game developer working full-time as a software engineer while pursuing an M.S. in Game Programming. I'm passionate about creative problem solving and modular design. With 2.5 years of work experience as a software engineer, I am actively transitioning into professional game development.



Work experience

2018-10 - PRESENT BOSTON, UNITED STATES

Software Engineer Autonodyne

- Developed Android and Windows applications for controlling multiple sUAS (drones) using Unity3D and C#.
- Lead design and implementation of UX, optimized for Mobile platforms (tablet and phone) and ported to Windows platforms (tablet and PC).
- Unity3D Technical Lead
- AR/VR Technical Lead
- Simulated all market-leading AR headsets in a VR environment to allow for rapid prototyping of AR multi-sUAS control stations.

2020-01 - 2020-09 BOSTON, UNITED STATES

Software Engineering Manager Autonodyne

- Took on managerial responsibilities while continuing my role as an individual contributor
- Led a team of 5 software engineers and oversaw individual project development
- Ran weekly stand-ups, to ensure team's continued progress and re-assess priorities
- Managed interns, providing technical leadership
- Coordinated AR software design

(switched myself out of management upon starting graduate school in September 2020)



Skills

~ SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

C#
Unity 3D
Java
Python
C

~ DESIGN SOFTWARE

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop

~ MUSIC TECHNOLOGY

Pro Tools Logic

~ PLATFORM EXPERIENCE

Mobile development VR development PC development



Education

2020-09 - PRESENT

M.S. | Game Programming DePaul University

 I am currently finishing up my first year at DePaul University pursuing a masters degree in Game Programming (fully-remote).

2013-09 - 2017-05 BOSTON, UNITED STATES

B.M. | Professional Music Berklee College of Music

 Concentrations in Film Scoring and Contemporary Writing and Production (Focused on production, scoring, and sound design for mixed media)